

Front-End Developer + Designer

- New York City & Remote.
- ✓ jexica.ayran@gmail.com
- +1.510.931-8468
- http://jexica.design
- in linkedin.com/in/jexica

#### **EDUCATION**

2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP

**GENERAL ASSEMBLY**, remote.

2011-2016

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE

CALIFORNIA COLLEGE OF THE ARTS, SF, CA, US.

#### **SKILLS**

- Adobe CC: Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, AfterEffect
- ► Figma and Whimsical for wireframes and web design development.
- ► HTML, CSS, & Javascript.
- Full-stack applications with Ruby on Rails and Express with Node.js.
- Front-end web application development with React.
- Building secure full-stack applications with model-view-controller (MVC) and Representational State Transfer (REST).
- ➤ 3D modeling in Rhinoceros, Cinema4D, and grasshopper.
- Passionate to grow as a creative developer.

# **JEXICA AYRAN**

#### **ABOUT**

I am a creative developer with expertise in front-end web development and multidisciplinary design. My innate curiosity, passion, and optimistic demeanor influence my design solutions and quality projects.

After completing General Assembly's SEI Bootcamp, I am excited to create and collaborate on modern front-end web technologies.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineering Immersive: Engineering Fellow 07/2021 - 10/2021 General Assembly Remote.

- Completed 13 week long training program dedicated to prepare students to think like engineers and approach problems creatively in order to build the next generation of web applications and digital products.
- ▶ Built 3 comprehensive full stack web applications, gaining experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails.
- ▶ Programming, computer science fundamentals, solving algorithmic challenges and analyzing the computational complexity of algorithms using Big O notation.

### Freelance Web Developer & Creative Novo Arts and Independent.

09/2019 - current NYC, NY

- > Prioritizing online coding classes and polishing my digital designer skills, I part-timed as a Designer at a previous employer, Novo Arts, and other side projects.
- ► Mainly used Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Bridge), Sketchup or Rhino for 3D modeling.

#### Designer Novo Arts

02/2018 - 08/2018 Brooklyn, NY

- □ Graphic designer at a small fine arts fabrication and consulting firm:
- ► Actively communicated, assisted, collaborated, and interpreted the client's or director's vision, and took initiative at various stages with frequent deadlines.
- ► Projects ranged from photo edits, graphic posters, digital art / collages, wall coverings,
  - sculpture or furniture 3D models and renders.
- Updated marketing booklets, branding, portfolio photo edits, and presentation posters.
- ► Set up and use large Epson plotters for canvas and poster prints.

## Xpert, Driver Tech and Support Uber, Greenlight Hub

08/2015 - 05/2017 SF, CA

- Uber's Greenlight Hub is the Partner (driver) In-person Support.
- ► Onboarding new drivers, escalating serious account issues, and resolving tech and payment discrepancies.
- Informational sessions, Uber 101 classes, and often took the role of Spanish-English translator.
- Mastering programs required for work: Jira, Internal Tools, Asana, Workday, and Zendesk.